Hello and welcome back. Let us now describe the first image
【未完成版本】欢迎回来 我们来看第一个图像修复的例子
Inpainting model. That's going to base, be based on partial
这个例子基于我们上周学过的
differential equations that we learned the last week.
偏微分方程
But again, this is going to be self contained, we're going to understand
和上周一样 这周的知识也是独立的
exactly what kind of partial differential equation are we going to use?
我们将会学习用哪一种偏微分方程
When we talk about image in painting we talk about the following.
当谈到图像修复时 我们是指
We have an image. Here and we have a region.
有一幅图像 这里有一个区域
Where we want to change the content of the image.
我们想要改变图像上这个区域的内容
In this case it's the cable. Here.
在这幅图中 这是条绳子
Someone's going to provide us this. Image and painting.
这部分有时会提供给我们
Includes the topic where we basically have these two inputs into the system.
图像修复要求有两幅这样的图像作为系统的输入
We are not going to detect, this is a very subjective, very often a very
我们不会做图像检测 因为这是非常主观的
subjective topic about what is that we want to change.
我们每个人想要修改的内容依主观而不同
Maybe somebody wants to change the shoes. In this case, we want to change this.
有人可能想修改鞋子 此时 我们就要修改鞋子
Now, how we detect these. We talk a lot about segmentation.
那么如何检测想要修改的部分？ 我们要用到图像分割
So we can segment out objects. And those are the regions of missing
因此得分割出对象 也就是缺少信息的区域
information. We are going to call them origins to be
我们称之为待修复的原始图
inpainted. With these two images, we want to make,
利用这里的两幅图像
basically, in this case, the cable disappear.
我们想让绳子消失
We want to inpaint in. These regions.
将在这个区域进行修复
And the first topic we're going to discuss is how do we inpaint with rich,
接下来要讨论的第一个主题是
with information from the surrounding regions.
如何利用该区域周围的丰富信息来修复图像
We're not going to take information from very far away.
我们不会使用距离此区域很远地方的信息
We are only going to use information from the surrounding regions.
仅仅使用周围区域图像的信息
So we get two images. The original image and an image which is
因此我们得到两幅图像 一幅原始图像
a binary mask of the, representing the regions that we want to in paint.
另一幅是待修复区域的二值掩膜图像
When I personally started working on Image Inpainting with my group, we
当我和我的团队开始研究图像修复时
visited a professional restaurenteur, a professional curator at the Minneapolis
我们拜访了明尼阿波利斯美术馆的专业馆长 他同时也是一个专业的餐馆老板
Institute of arts. And we asked this person how do you
我们向他咨询如何修复和复原图像
inpaint, how do you restore? And its very interesting because they
他们的方法十分独特
were doing it the way that children draw. And here is the illustration.
类似于儿童的绘画 下面我来演示一下
We have a region to be inpainted and we have the image.
这里有待修复的区域以及图像
So, they first continue the boundaries of the regions.
首先它们延展出区域边缘
So, if there is a boundary here going inside the region to being painted.
因此如果在待修复区域里有一个边缘
So then they continue the boundary inside.
然后就延展出内部的边缘
The same way that a child would basically draw the outlines of the objects.
小孩正是用同样的方法来描画物体的轮廓
Then, they complete the color. So first, they continue the boundaries.
接着完成颜色的修复 因此 首先他们延展出边缘
Then, they propagate the colors inside the region.
然后把颜色扩散到区域内
And then, lastly, they normally add kind of noise because paintings, and in this
最后 他们通常会加入某种噪声以模仿绘图效果
case it was a professional restorator of paintings don't look flawed so you have
至此便完成了一个专业的画作修复 为了看起来没有瑕疵
to kind of add this granularity to make it look more natural.
必须加入这种颗粒噪声 使图像看上去更自然
And we are going to talk about these. First we will talk about these two steps.
接下来我们就要研究这些内容 首先讨论这两步
Then we are going to discuss a bit about this step which there are many techniques
然后再简单讨论下这步 它涉及到了许多技术
to do that. That's what.
大概就是这些内容
So remember, there's kind of a continuation of the geometry, basically
记住 首先是边缘的几何延拓
the boundary and then filling with the colors.
接着是颜色填充
It's like if this is water, we are going to let the water flow into the
就好比这儿是水 我们让它流进这个区域
region, but because we have the boundary, it's going to actually, the right water
但是由于边界的限制 实际上
is going to flow into the right regions. Now, the job is to design a partial
右边的水会流入右边的区域 现在要做的就是
differential equation that emulates this process.
设计一个偏微分方程来仿真这个过程
And here it is. So we have basically the image outside
就像这样 在这个区域外有图像
and we have a region of missing information inside.
但内部是缺损信息的区域
And we want to propagate the information from outside in.
我们要把外部的信息扩散到内部
The way we're going to do that is with this equation.
实现方法就是利用这个方程
This is the first component of imaging painting with partial differential
这是偏微分方程处理图像的第一个步骤
equations. So what's happening here?
这个方程具体含义是什么呢？
Is the information that we want to propagate.
L 代表我们需要要扩散的信息
I am not telling you yet what is that information.So is the information.
我现在不告诉你信息指什么
That we want to propagate. And n is the direction that we're
就把它看成我们要扩散的东西 向量N表示信息扩散的方向
propagating that information. So n is the direction that we're doing
所以我们就沿N方向做扩散操作
the propagation. Now look what happens here.
现在来看看这儿发生了什么
We have gradient l meaning the change of L.
这里得到L的梯度 它表示L的变化
Inner product with N = 0. This is a change of A and it's projected,
和向量N做内积得到0 这儿是L的变化
because of the inner product, into N, the direction of propagation and we want it
因为内积作用 它被投影到N方向 也就是扩散方向
to be equal to zero. So this is of course a vector.
我们想要这个投影等于零 这儿当然是一个向量
It's the gradient of information. So we have a vector.
这是信息的梯度 因此我们得到一个向量
And we want that vector to be perpendicular to the direction that we
同时让这个向量垂直于扩散方向
are propagate, and we're have, so this is going to be the gradient of L, and this
所以这是L的梯度
is going to be the direction. We want them to be basically
这是扩散的方向 我们要它们互相垂直
perpendicular in the sense that we want to propagate information L.
也就是说 我们要用这个方法来扩散信息并且不改变它
In such a way that is it does not change, it does not change in the direction of
也就是信息在传播方向上没有改变
the propagation.That's exactly what it means propagating information.
这就是信息传播的具体内容
I move it in the direction that is constant along that direction.
让信息沿着一个方向保持不变地扩散
That's what this equation is basically telling us.
这就是这个方程所揭示给我们的
That L, the information is constant in the direction of propagation, constant
信息L在扩散方向上保持不变 在这些方向上都维持恒定
along these directions. Now how do we solve this with partial
那么如何引入偏微分方程来求解呢？
differential equations? Assume that the image is I.
假设这个图像用 I 表示
[SOUND] Now, we have this and we want to deform the image, we want to change the
现在已知这个方程 我们想要变形和修改这幅图像
image, this is a partial differential equation, in such a way that at the end,
这些操作在数学上就对应一个偏微分方程 经过某种方式最后等于零
we get this equal to zero. We have seen how to do that when we're
在我们讨论欧拉-拉格朗日方程时 已经知道如何做到这一点
talking about Euler-Lagrange equations. When we want something to be equal to
如果令某个量等于零
zero, how do I deform the image in order to accomplish that?
那我对图像做什么操作才能达到这个目的呢？
Let's think for a second how to do that. Remember last week.
我们先想想该怎么做 回忆一下上周
How do we do that? Very simple.
当时我们是如何做的？ 非常简单
We basically do this. Let me just go back one sec.
让我们花一点时间回忆一下
We make the image change in time
首先 令图像在时间上的变化
according to what we want. Now, when this doesn't change anymore,
等于我们想要的这个式子 当图像不再改变时
meaning that steady state, we get this equal to zero.
也就是达到稳态时 这个式子等于零
That's the definition of steady state: no more change.
这就是稳态的定义——不再变化
Actually, the computer, when this very little change, we can stop.
实际上 在计算机里 当变化很小时就可认为不再变化
When this is ideally zero, we got what we wanted.
当它达到理想状态的零时 就得到了我们想要的
L. Constant in the direction of propagation.
L在扩散方向上保持恒定
So, this is actually a very simple trick. Every time you want to do something like
这是个非常简单的技巧 当你想得到
A = zero, whatever is A, some information of the image, you do dI dT = A.
A = 0 的形式时 A可能是图像的某些信息 可令 ∂I/∂t = A
And you run that to a steady state. That's basically what we did for the all
接着令它达到稳态 这就是我们对欧拉-拉格朗日方程的处理
day Lagrange. So this is the basic equation for this
这就是基本的图像修复方程
type of imaging painting. Now, we haven't finished.
但现在并没有结束
I have to tell you what's L and what's M. What's the information that we want to
接下来要告诉你L和N代表什么 我们想要扩散的信息是什么
propagate? And in which direction do we want to
以及往哪个方向上扩散
And there's a lot of art here.
这里涉及到许多巧妙的技巧
So I'm just giving you examples. I'm teaching you the concepts.
我会讲一些例子 给你们一些概念
And these are examples that are already very powerful.
这些例子经证明是非常有效的
But you can come with different examples. Now, let me start by the information.
你也可以举其他的例子 现在首先来看信息L
We want this propagation to be smooth. We don't want to see a big jump inside
我们要求扩散是平滑的 不希望待修复区域出现巨大的反差
the region that we are inpainting. If we see a big jump, we're going to
如果有巨大的反差 我们就会注意到那个区域
notice that. So we want it to be smooth.
所以我们要求平滑
So it has to be anything that represent basically smoothness in the image, and
所以任何能反映图像平滑性的量都可以表示L
one of the things that represent smoothness is the Laplacian of the image,
图像的拉普拉斯变换就是表征平滑度的一个量
the second derivative of the image represent smoothness.
图像的二阶导反映了平滑度
Now. Why not the first derivative?
为什么不是一阶导呢？
Wait a second, and you're going to understand why.
过一会你就会明白了
Because the first derivative is also a representation of this bothness.
【未完成翻译】因为一阶导数依旧反映了平滑度
Now, in which direction are we going to propagate?
现在的问题是 应该往哪个方向上扩散呢？
And now we go back to what we learned from professional restorators.
我们回顾一下从专业复原人员那学到的东西
They say, continue edges. Now, we know that if we have an edge, the
他们会延展出边缘 我们知道 如果有一个边缘
gradient of the image is perpendicular to the edge.
那么图像的梯度是和这个边缘垂直的
We learned that, that week, last week, so we are going to want to propagate along
我们上周学过 因此我们想沿着边缘扩散信息
the edges, which means that we have to take the perpendicular to the gradient,
也就是沿着梯度的垂直方向扩散
so n is the perpendicular to the gradient, as written here, or we can
所以N垂直于梯度 像这里写的这样
write that n is basically the gradient. But the perpendicular to it.
也可以这样写 N等于梯度 然后这里加个垂直符号
So that's important thing here, that we want to continue edges.
这个非常重要 我们要延展出边缘
And then, for that, we have to go perpendicular to the gradient.
然后为了求边缘 我们必须求梯度的垂直方向
And that basically also explains why we cannot take the first derivative of L.
这也解释为什么我们不能只求L的一阶导
Because if we were to put L. Equal to the first derivative, let's say
因为如果令L等于图像的一阶导 也就是梯度
the gradient. These two guys are always zero.
那么这两个量的内积永远等于零
So I'm not solving anything. Because the gradient and its
就不需要解任何方程了 因为梯度和它的垂直量做内积总是零
perpendicular are always zero. And I wanted basically to go kind of.
而我想要在这个方向得到一个常数
Constant in that direction. This is not enough.
求一阶导是不够的
There is also another reason why, okay this is always perpendicular, it's not
还有其他原因 当然 这两个量一直垂直是不太好
very good. Although remember we're taking the
依然记住我们需要得到L的梯度
gradient of L. But the other reason is because we want.
其他原因是 我们想要区域里的两个量平滑
Two things to be smooth inside. We want to continue the grey values
让区域内的灰度值保持平滑
inside to be smooth. We also want to con, continue the
同时 区域内的边缘也要求保持平滑
boundaries to be smooth inside, so we need higher order of the realities.
所以我们需要高阶导数来实现它
Not only because these two guys are perpendicular and then there's not enough
并不仅仅因为这两者互相垂直才不用一阶导 还因为缺少足够的信息
information, even if we take the gradient of L, which is what actually N pending is
即使我们求得了L的梯度 梯度的方向与图像修复扩散的方向一致
propagating. We want to go a bit higher order so we
所以我们还要更高的阶数以便得到更多的平滑信息
get even more smoothness. And as I said, the Laplacian is one of
正如我所说 拉普拉斯变换是衡量平滑度的最简单的方法
the simplest measures of smoothness. So, we get smoothness.
我们便得到了
In the opposite direction or perpendicular to the gradient or on the
在等照度线方向或者梯度的垂直方向 或等高线方向的平滑度
level line's direction. And that basically gives us our equation.
这样我们就得到了方程
So, we have the change of l. And this is the normal, is the
所以这个表示L的变化 而这个是法线
perpendicular to the gradient. What we're going to get at the end of
它垂直于梯度方向 最终得到什么呢 【未完成版本】
this, when we get to steady state, when this becomes zero we basically get that
当达到稳态时 这个式子等于零
the Laplacian became constant along the edges.
这样图像的拉普拉斯变换沿着边缘方向就是一个常数
And we have propagated the Laplacian along the edges.
我们沿着边缘扩散拉普拉斯变换
That's what basically this basic equation makes and once again you just discretize
这就是基本方程所做的 再次地你只要在计算机中将它离散化
it in the computer and you run it and you get Image Inpainting.
接着运行它 你就实现了图像修复
You get propagation from outside in. Every differential equation has to have
你从外部向内部扩散 每个微分方程都必须有边界条件
boundary conditions. So, if this is my image and this is my
如果这是我的图像 而这是我要修复的区域
region to be in painting, what do I assume here?
我需要在这里做什么呢？
And these boundary conditions for this type of equations, a bit of a strange
对于这种有点奇怪的方程
equation, it has three derivatives, two because of the Laplacian, one more
它的边界条件有三个导数 两个来自拉普拉斯变换
because of the gradient. Remember.
还有一个来自梯度 回忆一下
We talked about this in the past. But the Laplacian is the second
我们以前讨论过这个
derivative of the image. In one direction plus the second
拉普拉斯变换是图像在一个方向上的二阶导
derivative of the image in the other direction.
加上图像在另一个方向上的二阶导
And then we take the gradient of this. And we get a third derivative of
然后再对它求梯度 这样就得到了第三个导数
considering both gray values and edges in the boundary and those are smoothly
同时考虑了边界内的灰度值和边缘 它们都光滑向内扩散
propagating inside thanks to have basically the Laplacian here and these
这是因为拉普拉斯变换的作用
are as we talked the level lines of the image the isopoles the regions of edges,
这些法线N就是我们所说的图像的等高线 或者等照度线方向
the directions of edges. These are very simple but very, very
或者说是边缘的方向 这些方程非常简单
interesting equation. Let us see some examples.
但是非常有趣 让我们看一些例子
So always when you do image processing, start with very simple examples to see
当你做图像处理时 一般从非常简单的例子入手检验发生了什么
what's happening. And here is a very simple example.
这儿就有一个简单的例子
White is the region. Then it's to be inpainted.
白色的为待修复的区域 我们来修复它
And you can see here that there is a very smooth continuation.
可以看到这儿有非常光滑的延续
Really, really nice. A smooth continuation.
非常非常美妙 光滑的延续
It continues the boundaries nice. It, of course, continues the colors,
边界
black and grey. But even more, more important, it really
更重要的是 它补全了这个圆
completes the circle. It doesn't know that there is a circle
它并不知道这里有个圆
there. It just goes in the normal direction.
它只是简单地在法线方向上延拓
Perpendicular to the normal direction in the edge direction.
垂直于法线方向的是边缘方向
Remember the gradient is in this direction.
记住梯度在这个方向
The perpendicular to the gradient is in this direction.
垂直于梯度方向的是这个方向
So it's going and it's filling in. Inside the region.
所以它就向待修复的区域延拓并且填充
Propagating information in that direction.
在那个方向想扩散信息
Really, really nice result. Of course, if it works only in artificial
非常棒的结果 当然 如果这个只能作用在人造图像上
images it's not very good. Hopefully, it works on the, also on real
就不是那么棒了 但愿它也能在真实的图像上工作
data. Here is an example.
这里举一个例子
What is being impainted? The letters.
要修复的是什么呢？
We wrote on top of this image. This is a nice image of New Orleans.
是写在图像之上的字母覆盖的区域 这是一张新奥尔良的美景图像
And we draw with a basic rough and tough and boom, the letters are gone.
我们简单粗暴地处理一下 很快地 字母消失了
So the regions to be painting are all these letters and we go inside and we
所以要修复的区域是所有这些字母覆盖的区域
make the letters disappear. We're propagating information from
我们把外部的信息扩散到里面
outside in. So hard to see here and now you get the
在这里很难看清  而现在你得到一张非常漂亮的图像
very nice image where we invented the information that is covered by the
在被字幕覆盖的区域我们创造了信息
letters. Based on information that is surrounding
根据字母周遭的信息
the letters. Very nice result, I think.
我认为这是非常漂亮的结果
Here is another example of basically an image that has deteriorations and
这是另一个例子 这是一张恶化和退化的照片
degradation. The red are the images, the regions, that
红色的表示要修复的图像区域
we are going to in paint. Sometimes, you mark regions that are a
有时 你标记的区域要比
bit larger than the actual missing information.
实际上缺失信息的区域要大一点点
Look here. Is very thing.
看这里 这条线很细
You do it a bit larger. It's like giving an impulse.
你可以把它标注地大些 就像给它一个冲激一样
So this is propagated from outside, in. You start from a, be far away.
这是从外部扩散到内部 从稍远的外部开始扩散
It helps you have to move even more smooth as we want.
它移动地甚至比你需要的还要光滑
And here are the results. And it looks pretty good, some place you
这就是结果 它看起来很棒 你可能会在这里看到一些小错误
might see a tiny error here because it's covering a lot of the eye of this girl,
因为这个女孩的眼睛被遮盖了太多了
so it's very difficult to invent information when there is nothing in the
所以当附近区域没有信息来暗示需要填入的内容时
surrounding area that hints about what needs to be basically put in.
创造信息是很难的
But of course you get an extremely good. At least initial result looks almost
当然你已经做得很好了 至少初步的结果看起来几乎完美了
excellent and the a professional restorator you see different programs may
接着 如果需要的话 采用不同程序的专业修复
basically be able to go and repair only that tiny region if needed to.
可以只对那个微小的区域进行修复
Sometimes, there's no need for that. Here is the original one.
有时是没必要那么做的 这是原图
We have already seen it. A person is jumping with a cable.
我们已经看过它了 一个人绑着绳子跳出去
Now the cable is gone, and now you see a zooming region.
现在绳子没了 你看到的是放大的区域
Once again, look how nice the socks continue.
再看一次袜子多么棒地延展
Very nice continuation of this thread H because that's what we wanted, we were
在条纹边缘非常棒延展 因为这就是我们要的
continuing HX that's exactly what we wanted, and that's exactly what this type
连续的边缘 这是我们想要的 而这就是这类算法所起的作用
of algorithm does. So, on our example, just a special
所以在我们的例子中 起到了特殊的效果
effect, let's just look at what's happening here.
让我们看看这里发生了什么
And basically they're all gone. I'm going to just show you that again.
他们都消失了 我将再展示一遍
There are people in the boat and they're all gone.
在船上有人 然后他们都消失了
We're basically in-painting what's basically been covered by the people
我们只是修复了这些被船上坐着的人遮盖的区域
sitting on the boat and basically they're all gone.
然后这些人就消失了
Again, in-painting means modifying an image in a form that is then
再说一次 修复意味着某种形式上不可检测的图像修改
non-detectable, at least by the regular consumer.
至少对于普通消费者是这样的
Here is another example of, we have scratches and now the scratches are gone
这是另外一个例子 图片上有一些划痕 现在划痕都消失了
basically, we basically removed those scratches.
我们移走了所有划痕
We inpaint in the information from the surrounding areas and again, looks very
用附近区域的信息来修复图像 这看起来很棒
nice. It looks very natural as it was before it
它看起来非常自然 就像没被抓损过一样
was all scratched. Now there is one example.
这里有一个例子
And this is the last example I want to show in this video where it's actually
这是这次视频里我要展示的最后一个例子
not very hard to detect the regions that need to be inpainted.
在这个例子里 检测需要修复的区域实际上并不是太难
In other previous examples we, basically the user, defined somehow the regions.
在之前的其他例子中 用户定义了要修复的区域
Now, this is an example, for example, of wireless transmission of images.
现在这是一个无线传输的图像的例子
Remember, images are transmitted, are restored, using JPEG.
记住 图像使用 JPEG 来传输、存储
JPEG works in blocks. What happens is, if when you're
JPEG按块工作 当你传输一个图像时
transmitting an image, there's a signal drop.
会发生信号丢失
For example, on the cell phone. So half a block gets dropped.
比如说在移动电话的情形中 一半的块丢失了
Now, signal drops are not very hard to detect, and basically.
现在 信号丢失并不是很难检测
You, you have no signal and you detected it.
你没收到信号 于是就检测到了
Okay? So when there's a drop you can say, hey,
懂了吧？ 所以当这里发生了丢失 你可以说: 嘿
I'm basic going to recover that block by mention painting.
我要用上面谈到的修复算法来恢复丢失的块
And that's what we are simulating here. And this is the original and all these
那就是我们在这里所模拟的东西 这是原始图像
blocks that you see here basically are dropped signals, simulation of dropped
在这看到的所有的块都是丢失的信号 是对丢失信号的模拟
signal. You see that there's no signal, you plug
你发现这里没有信号 就将它加入还原
that into a painting and then boom, you reconstruct your image.
很快 你就修复了这个图像
Let me show you that again, you basically see signal drop.
让我再展示一遍给你 你发现了信号丢失
And you reconstruct. So basically you may have a better
然后你修复了 你可能有一个更好的移动电话
cellular phone, a cellular phone that detect signal drop in images and boom
一个可以检测图像的信号丢失然后很快做完图像修复的移动电话
does imaging painting, this is still JPEG, still the person that is sending it
图像仍然是JPEG格式
to you doesn't know. That the signal might drop.
传输给你这张图像的人不知道信号可能丢失
At the receiver end, you see a signal drop.
在接受终端 你发现了信号丢失
This actually can help even compression. You can drop on purpose some of the
这实际上能够帮助压缩 你可以故意丢掉一些块
blocks, because we know how to recover them with image in painting, and in that
因为你知道如何用图像修复来还原他
way, you basically improve the compression ratio.
这样就提高了压缩率
Some blocks are very easy to recover, and then you can actually not even send them
一些块很容易被恢复 事实上你并不需要发送或者存储它们
or not even store them. Makes the reconstruction a bit more
在计算开销上增加了一丁点
computationally expensive, but makes the compression possibly much higher.
却可能使压缩率大幅升高
So this is the last example from this video.
这是该视频的最后一个例子
But there is one thing I haven't told you and that was on purpose just to keep you
但是还有一件事情我还没告诉你 我故意要让你多想想
wondering a bit. I gave you the equation of.
我给了你们图像修复的等式
Image in painting, but here we have three colors.
但是我们有三种颜色
How do we do that? How do we go from that equation that I
我们该这么做？ 我们该如何从我给你们的等式转换到多种颜色的情况？
gave you before to colors? Remember the equation was something like
记住 等式为
IT equal gradient of ii and the I. In a product.
It等于I做拉普拉斯变换之后的梯度与I的梯度的垂直向量的内积
Gradient I. Perpendicular, so.
所以
You can basically do this for each one of the channels.
你可以在每一个通道运用该式
Lets say in red, green, blue or in any other color space.
也就是说在红色、绿色、蓝色或者其它颜色空间
Or you can think about extending this to color images, to vectors.
或者你可以想办法把它扩展到彩色图像 扩展到向量
We know the concept of gradient for color vectors and we can basically define the
我们知道彩色向量梯度的概念
Laplacian for color vectors as well. So, both possibilities exist.
我们也可以定义彩色向量得拉普拉斯变换 所以 存在两种可能的办法
You can treat every color independently or you can try to use definition of
你可以单独处理每一个颜色或者你可以尝试
vectorial fields for these, every component here Laplacian and gradient in
使用矢量场的定义 将每一个部分 比如拉普拉斯变换和梯度
vectorial fashion. All the examples I show you, every color
改变为矢量场的形式 所有我展示给你看的例子
is treated independently. So, this is an example of imaging pending
都是分开处理每个颜色的 以上是一些由偏微分方程式进行图像处理的例子
with partial differential equations. Next video, I'm going to show you an
在下个视频中 我将向你展示
example of energy painting with variational formulations that we learned
一些使用上星期学过的变分公式来进行的图像修复
last week. Very simple variation of formulation that
一些很简单的变分公式
will lead us to also a very nice energy painting technique based on the same
将会带给我们一个非常棒的图像修复技术 它基于颜色和边界的相同扩散算法
colors of propagation and boundaries. I'm looking forward to seeing you in the
很希望能在下一节视频中见到你
next video. Thank you.
谢谢 【未完成版本】